Guide to the Ray Benson Accessions
The Wittliff Collections
- Accession 2019-128, 8 Linear Feet 2 posters
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; The Austin Chronicle, Vol. 17, No. 4 with Ray Benson on cover, December 5, 1997 (Box 3333, Folder 23)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Awards ceremony programs: Technical Excellence and Creativity Awards, and The 1996 Governor's Award Tribute Honoring Lyle Lovett Hosted by Ray Benson and Ann Richards, 1995-1996 (Box 3334, Folder 1)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; NARAS Grammy Awards – Programs and final nominations 18th, 30th, 38th – 40th annual ceremonies, 1972-1998 (Box 3334, Folder 2)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; BMI Country Music Awards programs, 1982-1986 (Box 3334, Folder 3)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; 14th Annual Country Music Association Awards Show: The Official Yearbook and Guide, 1980 (Box 3334, Folder 4)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; The Rhythm & Blues Foundation 8th and 9th Annual Pioneer Awards programs, 8th Annual Pioneer Awards discography, 1997-1998 (Box 3334, Folder 5)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Academy of Country Music 29th Annual Awards ceremony program, 1994 (Box 3334, Folder 6)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Showbiz Weekly Las Vegas entertainment magazine. Article on Asleep at the Wheel, pg. 61, September 22, 1996 (Box 3334, Folder 7)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Country Music International Fan Fair Nashville, Tennessee program, Liberty Records and Patriot Records host, Ray Benson, pg. 12, 70th anniversary of the Grand Old Opry, pg. 63, 1995 (Box 3334, Folder 8)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; 1991 Texas Inauguration program, Ann Richards, Governor. Gala performers Asleep at the Wheel, January 14-15, 1991 (Box 3334, Folder 9)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; The Long Center for the Performing Arts, Austin, Texas grand opening bound photo album inscribed "Ray, Thanks for making this a magical weekend. Love ya Bobbie T.", May 28-29th, 2008 (Box 3334, Folder 10)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Commemorative plaque "Still The King" with Ray Benson Texan Theater Thank You Ray! Bob Wills Heritage Foundation Bob Wills Fiddle Festival and Concert, October 15, 2015 (Box 3334, Folder 11)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Plaque presented to Ray Benson by Texas State University, San Marcos, Texas for "Studies in Entrepreneurship Visiting Entrepreneur", presented by College of Business Administration, March 2, 2004 (Box 3334, Folder 12)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Award presented to Asleep at the Wheel by the Country Music Association for Awards Finalist for Vocal Group of the Year, framed, 1987 (Box 3334, Folder 13)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Ephemera 1. Two tickets to the 32nd Annual Grammy Awards 2. United States of America Passport for Ray Benson Seifert, 3. Texas Department of Public Safety chauffer license for Ray Benson Seifert, 4. Monthly date book, 5. Spiral bound Weekly Minder, 6. Smithsonian Institution membership card for Ray Seifert, 7. D.A. Weibring A.R.C. Pro/AM contestant button for Ray Benson, 8. Asleep at the Wheel Bob Wills Tribute Tour "94" guest pass, 9. NARAS Trustees Meeting VIP pass, 10. Outdoor Junction Concert, Montana Asleep at the Wheel ticket, 11. Official 3 Stooges Fan Club membership certificate for Ray Benson, 1963-2018 (Box 3334, Folder 14)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Western Swing Music Hall of Fame induction award presented to Ray Benson, lucite music note mounted on wooden base, undated (Box 3334, Folder 15)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; B&W, 11.5 x 14.5 photograph of Ray Benson on outdoor stage, undated (Box 3335, Folder 1)
  - "Old Press 1972-1997"; Country Music Association Citation of Merit presented to Asleep at the Wheel as a finalist in the Annual Country Music Awards for Instrumental Group of the Year, 1977 (Box 3335, Folder 2)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Special Citation of Achievement presented by BMI to Paw Paw Music for 1 million broadcast performances for "My Baby Thinks He's a Train". Includes correspondence from Frances W. Preston, President & CEO of BMI, undated (Box 3335, Folder 3)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Billboard: The International Newsweekly of Music, Video and Home Entertainment, 100th Anniversary Issue 1894-1994 Special Collector's Edition, November 1, 1994 (Box 3335, Folder 4)
  - "Old-Newsletters, Press kits, Photos"; Posters and record flats 1. Asleep at the Wheel 10 album cover bi-fold record flat, Epic Records, 2. Don Walser Down at the Sky-Vue Drive-in record flat, Sire Records, 3. Asleep At The Wheel Tribute to the Music of Bob Wills and The Texas Playboys record flat, Liberty Records, 4. 98.1 KVET radio station birthday poster for Ray Benson, "Saluting a Genuine Texas Original…Happy Birthday Ray!", 5. The Pojoaque Chapter of the Universal Life Church presents Asleep at the Wheel featuring Ray Benson Jan 20 Line Camp, 1987, 1993, 1998, undated (Box 3335, Folder 5)
  - Turn Key Productions Indian Summer Country & Bluegrass Festival poster, September 23-24, 1978 (Map-case 4, Item 1)
  - A Ride With Bob: From Austin to Tulsa, A Musical Drama About the Life and Legend of Bob Wills poster, March 3-6, 2005 (Map-case 4, Item 2)
- Accession 2020-075, 8 Linear Feet
  - Ray Benson Seifert's birth announcement, 1951 (Box 3503, Folder 1)
  - Congregation Rodeph Shalom bulletin with announcement of Ray Benson Seifert's Bar Mitzvah, March 2, 1964 (Box 3503, Folder 2)
  - Nomination certificate presented to Asleep at the Wheel for Best Country Instrumental Performance for "Fat Boy Rag", National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences. Includes letter of congratulations to Ray Benson, 1997 (Box 3503, Folder 3)
  - "Awards: Certificates and Grammy Nom:"; Grammy nomination certificates and letters of congratulations for Asleep at the Wheel, National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences, 1977-1990 (Box 3503, Folder 4)
  - "Photos – October 1993"; Four (4) B/W 8 x 10 photographs of Asleep at the Wheel and two (2) B/W Polaroids of Ray Benson (Box 3503, Folder 5)
  - "Ray Resume/BIOCAP"; Newspaper and magazine clippings pertaining to Ray Benson and Asleep at the Wheel, Pennsylvania Country Music Association certificate, bicycling schedule for "The Dinah Shore Show", WYNK Radio country music chart, 1976, 2000, undated (Box 3503, Folder 6)
  - "Ray's Guitar Poses"; Two (2) B/W 8 x 10 photographs and one (1) 8 x 12 color photograph of Ray Benson, 1991-1992 (Box 3503, Folder 7)
  - "Rates and Price Lists"; Equipment serial numbers and price lists, Guitar City price list, 1971, undated (Box 3503, Folder 8)
  - "Nashville Now" rundown schedule, Asleep at the Wheel performing, 1992 (Box 3503, Folder 9)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel"; Attendee packet for the 52nd Presidential Inauguration of William Jefferson Clinton. Performance schedules, lists of clubs and restaurants, city and metro map and area attractions, 1993 (Box 3503, Folder 10)
  - Dallas Observer, Number 558. Issue sent to Ray Benson from Laura [Lynch], Dixie Chicks All Cowgirl Band. Includes note to Ray Benson from Laura [Lynch], 1993 (Box 3503, Folder 11)
  - Itinerary for the SKOL Country Festival, San Paulo, Brazil, Asleep at the Wheel performing, August 26- September 3, 1991 (Box 3503, Folder 12)
  - Texas House Simple Resolution declaring August 2, 1978 "Asleep at the Wheel Day" in Texas, 2 copies, July 26, 1978 (Box 3503, Folder 13)
  - Photocopy of an Asleep at the Wheel pen and ink cartoon, undated (Box 3503, Folder 14)
  - Grammy nomination for Asleep at the Wheel's track "One O'clock Jump" for Best Country Instrumental Performance, National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences, January, 1979 (Box 3503, Folder 15)
  - Invitation to "An Evening of Our American Musical Culture" hosted by Rick Blackburn and Tammy Wynette of CBS Records, July 24, 1987 (Box 3503, Folder 16)
  - Letter to Ray Benson and Asleep at the Wheel from Johnny Gimble, original and photocopy, March 26, 1973 (Box 3503, Folder 17)
  - Invitation from Kent Finlay to a birthday party for Kenneth Threadgill, undated (Box 3503, Folder 18)
  - Soap Creek Saloon invitation to CMA party and show featuring Willie Nelson and Marsha Ball, 1976 (Box 3503, Folder 19)
  - Tongue-in-cheek Asleep at the Wheel personnel record for Ray Benson, undated (Box 3503, Folder 20)
  - Review of Asleep at the Wheel's album The Wheel Keep on Rollin' emphasizing the twenty-fifth anniversary of the band, November, 1975 (Box 3503, Folder 21)
  - Asleep at the Wheel awards and nominations list by year, 1975-1996 (Box 3503, Folder 22)
  - Asleep at the Wheel press kit, 2001 (Box 3503, Folder 23)
  - Asleep at the Wheel/Shady Grove Wild Basin Celebrity Golf Classic invitation. Includes Asleep at the Wheel Guitar pick, September 23, 1996 (Box 3503, Folder 24)
  - Telegram to Ray Benson from Jimmy Bowen congratulating Benson on 4th Grammy, 1994 (Box 3503, Folder 25)
  - Letter and crossword puzzle sent to Ray Benson from Johnny Gimble, October 21, 1977 (Box 3503, Folder 26)
  - The National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences 18th Annual Grammy Awards pre-telecast program, February 28, 1976 (Box 3503, Folder 27)
  - Letter to Asleep at the Wheel from The Academy of Country Music regarding Asleep at the Wheel's nomination for band of the year, January 31, 1977 (Box 3503, Folder 28)
  - Telegram to Ray Benson from James Wyble thanking Benson for album and lyrics, May 20, 1977 (Box 3503, Folder 29)
  - Thank you note to Ray Benson from Huey Lewis, undated (Box 3503, Folder 30)
  - Note to Ray Benson from Aaron Watson regarding Bob Wills postage stamp, undated (Box 3503, Folder 31)
  - Note to Ray Benson from Michael (no surname) regarding digital conversion of Bob Wills album. Includes five (5) color photographs of master recording sheets, 1973 (Box 3503, Folder 32)
  - Letter to Steve McPherson, ABC Television from Liz Smith regarding Ray Benson's musical "A Ride with Bob", October 31, 2006 (Box 3503, Folder 33)
  - Birth announcement for Samuel Lightning Seifert, November 22, 1983 (Box 3503, Folder 34)
  - My Father's Place concert bill, September 27-29, 1977 (Box 3503, Folder 35)
  - Letter to Ray Benson from Congressman Lloyd Doggett, Texas regarding White House Lawn performance, June 6, 2012 (Box 3503, Folder 36)
  - Invitation to the Austin City Limits Special Tribute to Django Reinhardt "Swingin' Over the Rainbow", August 22, 1981 (Box 3503, Folder 37)
  - KLRU Opening Night Production Timeline and program for opening night of Austin City Limits Live at the Moody Theater, February 24, 2011 (Box 3503, Folder 38)
  - Scene from the movie Wild Texas Wind. Includes note to "Ray and Dolly", undated (Box 3503, Folder 39)
  - The Austin Symphony Centennial Season program, 2011-2012 (Box 3503, Folder 40)
  - Pre-Telecast Program for the 33rd Annual Grammy Awards, February 20, 1991 (Box 3503, Folder 41)
  - "How to Make a Living on the Road Livable" by Ray Benson. Guide to surviving life on the road, undated (Box 3503, Folder 42)
  - Two (2) 8 x 10 B/W photographs, Asleep at the Wheel performing and Jay's Famous Lounge and Cock Pit, undated, 1979 (Box 3503, Folder 43)
  - Handwritten Asleep at the Wheel set list and dedication list, undated (Box 3503, Folder 44)
  - Letter to Ray Benson from Brady Dryer, University of Texas Press, regarding publication of Benson's memoir Comin' Right at Ya: How a Jewish Yankee Hippie went Country, or, the Often Outrageous Story of Asleep at the Wheel, June 15, 2015 (Box 3503, Folder 45)
  - Asleep at the Wheel TV logo, undated (Box 3503, Folder 46)
  - Asleep at the Wheel show poster, Route 66 Tour Bob Wills' Place on Main Street, May 8, 1992 (Box 3503, Folder 47)
  - 35th Annual Grammy Awards invitation. Asleep at the Wheel nominated in Category 35, Best Country Instrumental Performance for "Black and White Rag", February 24, 1993 (Box 3503, Folder 48)
  - One (1) copy of Best in Texas music magazine signed by Aaron Watson, Vol. 4 No. 3, April, 2004 (Box 3503, Folder 49)
  - Mercer and Associates press release for the album Asleep at the Wheel Tribute to the Music of Bob Wills and The Texas Playboys, November 3, 1993 (Box 3503, Folder 50)
  - Letter to Ray Benson from Charlie Daniels regarding the ACM Pioneer Award, May 6, 1998 (Box 3503, Folder 51)
  - Liberty Records press release and promo materials for Asleep at the Wheel Tribute to the Music of Bob Wills and The Texas Playboys, September, 1993 (Box 3503, Folder 52)
  - Photocopy of Billboard "Hot Country" singles chart week ending, February 13,1988 (Box 3503, Folder 53)
  - "Music in the Air" summer on the Square Concert Series program, undated (Box 3503, Folder 54)
  - 30th Annual Grammy Awards Pre-Telecast Awards program, March 2, 1988 (Box 3503, Folder 55)
  - Asleep at the Wheel Bob Wills Tribute featuring Lyle Lovett, Austin KLRU shoot, crew roster, set lists and shoot schedule, December 20, 1993 (Box 3503, Folder 56)
  - Bismeaux Records promo/marketing sheet for the Asleep at the Wheel and Leon Rausch album It's a Good Day, 2010 (Box 3503, Folder 57)
  - Printout of Ray Benson's speech introducing George Strait, final performance of Strait's Farewell Tour, AT&T Stadium, Dallas, Texas, June 7, 2014 (Box 3503, Folder 58)
  - Thank you note to Ray Benson from Broadus A. Spivey, President, State Bar of Texas, October 21, 2016 (Box 3503, Folder 59)
  - Vince Gill Country Celebrity Basketball Tournament and Concert program, November 5, 1990 (Box 3503, Folder 60)
  - Printout draft of Ray Benson's memoir Comin' Right at Ya: How a Jewish Yankee Hippie went Country, or, the Often Outrageous Story of Asleep at the Wheel, no date. Note: pages are not in order, undated (Box 3503, Folder 61)
  - 5th Annual Havelock Country Jamboree program, August 12-14, 1994 (Box 3503, Folder 62)
  - "Past AATW Newsletters"; Issues of As the Wheel Turns newsletter and tour schedules, 1995-2002 (Box 3503, Folder 63)
  - Honky Tonkin': A Guide to Music USA. British travel guide highlighting American Music scene, venues and record shops, undated (Box 3503, Folder 64)
  - 35th M&T Syracuse Jazz Fest program, June, 8-10, 2017 (Box 3503, Folder 65)
  - Unanimous Consent of Trustees, Rhythm and Blues Foundation, May 12, 1988 (Box 3503, Folder 66)
  - Letter to Ray Benson from Dolly Parton regarding Asleep at the Wheel's 25th Anniversary, May 17, 1995 (Box 3503, Folder 67)
  - Telegram to Ray Benson from Ricky Van Shelton congratulating Benson on a Grammy award, 1989 (Box 3503, Folder 68)
  - Letter to Ray Benson from Jan Lewan regarding meeting at the Grammy Awards. Includes color photograph of Lewan with Benson, Mach 9, 1995 (Box 3503, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence to Ray Benson and Asleep at the Wheel, 1977-1997 (Box 3503, Folder 70)
  - Draft script for the 10th Annual Technical Excellence and Creativity Awards, Ray Benson presenter, 1994 (Box 3503, Folder 71)
  - Texas medal of Arts Awards, 2017 (Box 3503, Folder 72)
  - Austin City Limits Hall of Fame program. Asleep at the Wheel, inductees, 2015 (Box 3503, Folder 73)
  - Asleep at the Wheel Press photo, circa 1970 (Box 3503, Folder 74)
  - Awards, certificates and proclamations, Ray Benson and Asleep at the Wheel, 1989-1996 (Box 3503, Folder 75)
  - "The Day of Texas in Prague" Prague, The Czech Republic. Foreign investment program booklet outlining the economic and legislative environment and business opportunities in the Czech Republic, October 11-17, 1994 (Box 3503, Folder 76)
  - "Bob Wills Stuff"; Press materials related to the album Asleep at the Wheel Tribute to the Music of Bob Wills and The Texas Playboys, 1993-1994 (Box 3503, Folder 77)
  - Letter to Ray Benson from Ivah "Miss Ivey" regarding the movie Wild Texas Wind starring Benson, Dolly Parton and Gary Busey, October 9, 1991 (Box 3503, Folder 78)
  - "For Use in Office Only"; Press materials related to the album Asleep at the Wheel Tribute to the Music of Bob Wills and The Texas Playboys, 1993-1994 (Box 3503, Folder 79)
  - House Simple Resolution declaring August 2, 1978 "Asleep at the Wheel Day" Texas, July 26, 1978 (Box 3503, Folder 80)
  - Event programs, includes Austin City Limits Reunion Special program, 1986, 1993-1994, 1998 (Box 3503, Folder 81)
  - The Journal of the American Academy for the Preservation of Old-Time Country Music Vol II, Number 2, includes note to Ray Benson, April, 1992 (Box 3503, Folder 82)
  - Country Music: Journal from Nevada newsletter. Two issues, Asleep at the Wheel 1993 issue, pg. 3 Bob Will tribute album review, 1993, 1994 (Box 3503, Folder 83)
  - ACL 20th Anniversary Gala Production schedule, undated (Box 3503, Folder 84)
  - Nominations for the 36th Annual Grammy Awards, Asleep at the Wheel nominated in Category 35, October 1, 1992-September 30, 1993 (Box 3503, Folder 85)
  - Asleep at the Wheel press releases and news clippings pertaining to albums, Japan's Country Gold Tour, Route 66 Tour and Asleep at the Wheel's 20th Anniversary, 1986, 1990 (Box 3503, Folder 86)
  - European tour itinerary for Asleep at the Wheel, Bellamy Brothers and Kathy Mattea, June 13-20, 1988 (Box 3503, Folder 87)
  - Photographs – Ray Benson, family and others, three (3) color photographs, undated (Box 3503, Folder 88)
  - Datebooks: 1. Black plastic spiral bound Monthly Minder, 2. Rolling Stone Book of Days spiral bound, 1977, 1980 (Box 3503, Folder 89)
  - Greeting cards and postcards. Birthday cards to Ray Benson and Christmas cards, 1991, 1998, undated (Box 3503, Folder 90)
  - Press/magazine clippings pertaining to Asleep at the Wheel and Ray Benson, 1980-2007, undated (Box 3503, Folder 91)
  - Press/newspapers and newspaper clippings pertaining to Ray Benson and Asleep at the Wheel, 1972-2011 (Box 3503, Folder 92)
  - Creem magazine. Review of Asleep at the Wheel's album Texas Gold, pg. 85, November, 1975 (Box 3503, Folder 93)
  - Country: The Music and the Musicians: Pickers, Slickers, Cheatin' Hearts & Stars. Promotional booklet, undated (Box 3503, Folder 94)
  - Veja São Paulo magazine. Skol Country Music Festival, pg. 14, Asleep at the Wheel, pg. 17, August – September, 1991 (Box 3503, Folder 95)
  - Texas Monthly. A celebration of Texas music Bob Wills issue, Vol 28, Issue 5, May, 2000 (Box 3503, Folder 96)
  - Texas Music magazine, Ray Benson cover, story pg. 46. Issue 38, 2009 (Box 3503, Folder 97)
  - Chutzpah magazine "Jews of Rock Part II" issue. Ray Benson and Luck Oceans pg. 38, Spring, 2012 (Box 3503, Folder 98)
  - Ephemera relating to Ray Benson and Asleep at the Wheel. Bumper stickers, backstage passes, VIP event passes, concert announcements, tickets, logos, 20th Anniversary stamp, 3 beer koozies, undated, 1990-2013 (Box 3503, Folder 99)
  - Ray Benson personal effects. Chauffeur license, membership cards, business cards, undated, 1984, 1994 (Box 3503, Folder 100)
  - Gavel presented to Ray Benson by Speaker of the House Tom Craddick, Texas House of Representatives, Christmas Tree Lighting, December 6, 2003 (Box 3504, Item 1)
  - Ballet Austin Balletomane Ray Benson, engraved award, 1999 (Box 3504, Item 2)
  - Goodwill Star Ray Benson, engraved star shaped award on green marble base, 1998 (Box 3504, Item 3)
  - Congregation Rodeph Shalom Confirmation Class composite photograph, 1967 (Box 3505, Folder 1)
  - Asleep at the Wheel posters, 1980, 1985, 1997, 2018, undated (Box 3505, Folder 2)
    General
    1. Asleep at the Wheel New Routes album flat, 2018 2. Backstage Ray Benson and Band, Saturday Dec. 20, 1980 3. Asleep at the Wheel, Medina County Fair Saturday Sept. 20, 1997 4. Asleep at the Wheel at Cowboy Club, Mexia, Texas Friday, June 28,
    1985 5. Ray Benson, I'm Changing the Face of Music, The Recording Academy,
    undated